<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pstools on Mark Holloway</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/pstools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pstools on Mark Holloway</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Mark Holloway</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/pstools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remote Windows management with PsTools, part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/06/02/remote-windows-management-with-pstools-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/06/02/remote-windows-management-with-pstools-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this third article on PsTools I talk about how to control V-Ray DR slaves remotely with the PsTools suite.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can launch the V-Ray render slave either as a service or in a stand-alone command line window. I prefer the latter, because it is easy to run into file server permissions issues with the service (it needs to be set up with proper access to the file server’s share). PsTools then will help launch and kill the V-Ray slave whether your weapon of choice is service or stand-alone command line window.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Windows management with PsTools, part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/05/15/remote-windows-management-with-pstools-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/05/15/remote-windows-management-with-pstools-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this second part of managing Windows machines using the PsTools suite, we will look at how to automate processes involving interacting with a server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Examples of task scripts for installing Nuke, Maya and V-Ray can be found further down in this article. A zip package is available here with all scripts explained in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-concept&#34;&gt;The concept&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the main concept; from a local managing machine (such as a laptop), have workstations and farm machines run a remote script to carry out a task. Have a look at the diagram below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Windows management with PsTools, part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/05/13/remote-windows-management-with-pstools-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/05/13/remote-windows-management-with-pstools-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the advantages of running Linux on render farm machines is the possibility to remotely manage them using the command line. However if you are running the farm on Windows, this is a whole different kind of story.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By using Mark Russinovich’s &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/bb896649&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PsTools&lt;/a&gt; it is possible to remotely manage render farm machines running on Windows with otherwise quite daunting tasks and without very little (if any) programming experience. You can use the suite of tools to easily restart machines, silently install software, manage services and environment variables or even distribute files onto remote machines on your network. The only prerequisite is that you are running Windows on both the managing machine as well as on the target machine and that both computers are residing on the same local network. Perfect for a small VFX shop without an elaborate IT department.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
